<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Guowei Lv</title>
    <link>https://www.lvguowei.me/categories/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Guowei Lv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 08:07:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lvguowei.me/categories/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Magit Tutorial - Bisect</title>
      <link>https://www.lvguowei.me/post/magit-tutorial-bisect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 08:07:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lvguowei.me/post/magit-tutorial-bisect/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s 5 o&amp;rsquo;clock on a sunny Friday afternoon, you are thinking where to have dinner with friends and such. The only thing you have to finish before you can go is to pull your colleage&amp;rsquo;s latest changes and make a demo build to customer. You pull, there are 20 commits all nicely structured, you are now giving yourself a pat on the back for teaching him to use rebase yesterday (by pointing him to these 2 wonderful articles 1 and 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magit tutorial - Rebase (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://www.lvguowei.me/post/magit-rebase-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 09:30:26 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lvguowei.me/post/magit-rebase-2/</guid>
      <description>In part I we went through how to use git rebase to modify commit history, things like reword a commit, squash multiple commits, split commit. In this part, we will talk about another common use case of rebase: rebase before merging branches.
Let&amp;rsquo;s first create a new repo and add one file.txt as the first commit.
apple pear peach cat dog snake Now we create a feature branch from master branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magit tutorial - Rebase (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://www.lvguowei.me/post/magit-rebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 15:25:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lvguowei.me/post/magit-rebase/</guid>
      <description>Magit is arguably the best Git tool out there and also my favorite. It is a package in Emacs, and it is text based. In this tutorial, we will explore how to use it to tackle one of the more elusive topics in Git: Rebase.
In the beginning there was darkness Let&amp;rsquo;s create an empty repository and add one empty file to it.
git init touch file.txt git add .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>